A Calendar of The Jefferson Papers of the University of Virginia
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I: Dated Materials
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON LIST OF PAINTINGS, ETC., AT MONTICELLO., [182-].; AD. 11 pp. McGregor Library, #2958-b.
    Names 126 paintings, sculptures, medals, and other art works, often with artists and sources. Subjects are chiefly religious, classical, mythological, and historical.
    [3102]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON LIST OF HIS ART OBJECTS., [182-].; AD. 14 pp. Moyer-Jefferson Papers, #5291.
    Names 48 paintings and art works, often with artists and sources. Subjects are chiefly religious, classical, mythological, and historical.
    [3103]
  - DEED FOR THE SALE OF MONTICELLO., 1836 May 20.; ADS. 4 pp. #1533.
    Executed between James T. and Julia Ann Barclay and Uriah Phillips Levy. Recorded by Ira [?] Garrett, Clerk of Albemarle County Court.
  - LIST OF DRAWINGS DEPOSITED BY WILSON CARY NICHOLAS RANDOLPH WITH THE PROCTOR OF THE UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA., 1898 February 9 and March 26.; DS. 1 pp. In the hand of Thomas H. Carter(?). With: 1898 March 26. Wilson Cary Nicholas Randolph to Col. Thomas H. Carter. ALS. 1 pp. #171.
    A list of drawings by T. J. deposited at the University of Virginia. Randolph asks Carter to turn over the drawings to Mansfield White who "wishes to take them to the New York office & compare them with the list left there." The list is signed by Richard Mansfield White 1898 April 2 acknowledging receipt of the drawings.
- Series II: Miscellaneous Undated Items
  - DESIGN FOR A DESK., n.d.; Paper CX. 4 1/2 x 6 in. #6225.
    [N-436]
  - DRAWING FOR A LOCKING MECHANISM (?)., n.d.; #5533.
    [N-561]
  - ELEVATION AND PLANS OF DORMITORIES., Ink. "Range 589 feet. 6 inches." Paper CW. 15 1/2 x 7 1/4 in. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Elevation shows arches on first floor and wood columns above. Possibly another study for N-374.
    [N-377]
  - ELEVATION OF THREE-STORY DORMITORY WITH EIGHT ROOMS TO EACH FLOOR. THREE FLOOR PLANS., n.d.; Ink and wash. Paper CW. 13 x 10 in. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Probably studies for University of Virginia, not by Jefferson, possibly by General John Hartwell Cocke; see his letter of May 3, 1819, to Jefferson.)
    [N-374]
  - ELEVATION OF TWO-STORY DORMITORY WITH WINGS. ELEVATION OF ONE-STORY DORMITORY. TWO FIRST-FLOOR PLANS AND ONE SECOND-FLOOR PLAN., Ink and wash. Paper CW. 12 1/2 x 9 in. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Possibly another study for N-374.
    [N-375]
  - "A GARDEN SEAT BY MR. JONES. FROM CHAMBER'S KEW.", n.d.; Ink. Paper CW. 9 x 15 1/2 in. #171.
    Writing not by Jefferson, perhaps John Neilson. A study of rendering.
    [N-497]
  - GEOMETRY PROBLEM., n.d.; AD. 2 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Has notes by T. J. at foot on method of drawing an octagon, and demonstration on verso.
    [3168]
  - GRAPH PAPER., n.d.; 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Said to have belonged to T. J.
    [3146]
  - "THE HEWING OF STONE.", n.d.; Paper CN. Portion watermarked. 8 x 5 in. #171.
    [N-499]
  - MONTICELLO. ROUGH SKETCH OF OUTLINE OF HOUSE AND DEPENDENCIES., #9828.
    Authenticated in unidentified hand.
    [N-562]
  - NOTES ON MAKING A JOINT, WITH SAMPLE., n.d.; AD. 3 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533. See Nichols, N-379.
    In unidentified hand on lettercover addressed to T. J.
    [3112]
  - [N. P. TRIST'S] DESCRIPTION OF THOMAS JEFFERSON'S PRESSES AND THEIR CONTENTS., 2 pp. #15410-f.
    On verso of lettercover postmarked n.y. February 14.
    [3159]
  - A PAPER PROTRACTOR, HOMEMADE., n.d.; #171.
    [N-505]
  - "PLAN C." ELEVATION AND TWO PLANS OF TWO-STORY DORMITORY., Ink and wash. Paper CW. 12 x 8 3/4. RG-1/3/3.761.
    [N-376]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON ACCOUNT WITH [?]., n.d.; D. 1 pp. In unidentified hand. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Mentions Norton and Col. Nicholas.
    [3171]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON "ALGERINE CEMENT.", n.d.; Paper CW. 8 x 3 in. #171.
    [N-433]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON APOTHECARY'S SCALE., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. #38-755.
    Scale of equivalent weights. On verso: version of song, Bumpers Squire Jones, in hand of Martha Randolph. (See Gentlemen's Magazine, XIV 612).
    [2333]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON ARCHITRAVE OF THE ARCHES OF THE DINING ROOM AT MONTICELLO., n.d.; Paper AJ. 9 1/2 x 10 1/2 in. #171.
    Includes a note regarding Mr. Dinsmore. During the recent restoration, Milton Grigg, the architect, found a beam with Dinsmore's name written on it.
    [N-188]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON AUTOGRAPH to MR. BOTTA., n.d.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by St. Paul's School. #2212.
    [2335]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON BLANK DINNER INVITATION WITH STAGE OR MAIL SCHEDULE ON VERSO., n.d.; AD. 2 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Fredericksburg, Richmond, and Lynchburg.
    [3148]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON BREMO. ELEVATION., n.d.; #7298.
    [N-351b]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON BREMO. PLAN., n.d.; #7298.
    [N-351a]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON CHESS PROBLEM, STATED AND SOLVED., AD. 2 pp. Photostat. Original owned by James Monroe Museum and Memorial Library, Fredericksburg. #3159.
    [3170]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON COPY OF A BALLAD., n.d.; AD. 2 pp. Printed: Percy III no. 12. #38-753.
    Although Jefferson has been credited frequently with the authorship of a ballad, The King of France, this copy is a fragment of an old English ballad, Valentine and Ursine or Valentine and Orson, which is printed in Bishop Thomas Percy's Reliques of Ancient English Poetry as number 12 in his 3rd series, book 3. In his catalogue of 1783, Jefferson lists Percy's work as one of the volumes he intended to purchase.
    [2334]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON COPY OF LORD BYRON'S ENIGMA., n.d.; AD. 2 pp. #6696.
    [3153]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON DRAWING and SPECIFICATIONS for a GAME BAG., D. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    [2337, N-556]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON DRAWING and SPECIFICATIONS for SERPENTINE WALL of the UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA., AD. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by Samuel H. McVitty. Printed: Corks and Curls (Univ. of Va. annual) 1934 320-321. #1871-a.
    [2338]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON DRAWINGS., 10 pp. 8 T. J. AD. Section D printed: Fiske Kimball, "Jefferson and the Public Buildings of Virginia", Huntington Library Quarterly XII 3 (May 1949) figures 6-7, pp. 308-309, incorrectly attributed to the Coolidge Collection. RG-1/3/3.761.
    Rough drafts, finished plans, and specifications for various buildings.
    A. Two-story building. Elevation, first and second floor plans. Pen drawings, ink wash. Marked "Plan C".
    [2336, N-376]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON DRAWINGS., 10 pp. 8 T. J. AD. Section D printed: Fiske Kimball, "Jefferson and the Public Buildings of Virginia", Huntington Library Quarterly XII 3 (May 1949) figures 6-7, pp. 308-309, incorrectly attributed to the Coolidge Collection. RG-1/3/3.761.
    B. Three-story building. Elevation, three floor plans. Pen drawings, ink wash.
    [2336, N-374]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON DRAWINGS., 10 pp. 8 T. J. AD. Section D printed: Fiske Kimball, "Jefferson and the Public Buildings of Virginia", Huntington Library Quarterly XII 3 (May 1949) figures 6-7, pp. 308-309, incorrectly attributed to the Coolidge Collection. #770.
    C. Five floor plans; pencil sketches with ink specifications, showing varying arrangements of centrally located circular and elliptical rooms. Perhaps drawings for unidentified residences; or tentative sketches proposed for the Capitol and Governor's House in Richmond (actually constructed from other plans); or more probably sketches for the President's House in Washington, made in preparation for anonymous submission of an entry in the competition announced by the Commissioners of Federal Buildings, 1792.
    [2336, N-409, N-410]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON DRAWINGS., 10 pp. 8 T. J. AD. Section D printed: Fiske Kimball, "Jefferson and the Public Buildings of Virginia", Huntington Library Quarterly XII 3 (May 1949) figures 6-7, pp. 308-309, incorrectly attributed to the Coolidge Collection. #770.
    D. First and second floor plans for a square residence with north and south porticoes, wings connected to the main building by arcades; ink drawings. Students of Jeffersonian architecture have identified these drawings as (1) tentative studies for the President's House and (2) tentative studies for the Governor's House at Richmond. (See Fiske Kimball's article cited above). It may be noted that the one parlor shown occupies less than one ninth of the first floor, which is largely occupied by bedrooms, a nursery, etc.--a much simpler plan than that of the Governor's House at Williamsburg--suggesting that this plan may be for an unidentified country residence.
    [2336, N-281, N-282]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON DRAWINGS., 10 pp. 8 T. J. AD. Section D printed: Fiske Kimball, "Jefferson and the Public Buildings of Virginia", Huntington Library Quarterly XII 3 (May 1949) figures 6-7, pp. 308-309, incorrectly attributed to the Coolidge Collection. #861.
    E. Floor plan and cross section of elevation of a residence. Elevation labeled "Thos. Jefferson Archt. Longitudinal Section. Robt. Mills delr." Ink drawings showing details of interior.
    [2336, N-412, N-413]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON DRAWINGS., 10 pp. 8 T. J. AD. Section D printed: Fiske Kimball, "Jefferson and the Public Buildings of Virginia", Huntington Library Quarterly XII 3 (May 1949) figures 6-7, pp. 308-309, incorrectly attributed to the Coolidge Collection.
    F. See [7] and [1516] above for drawings of Monticello and Poplar Forest.
    [2336]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON ENDORSED WRAPPER: "SURVEYS OF SHADWELL.", AD. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [3163]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON ENDORSED WRAPPER: "SURVEYS OF LEGO., " AD. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [3164]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON EXTRACT FROM EDWARD YOUNG'S THE BROTHERS., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. #6643.
    Poem.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON LOGARITHM TABLES., n.d.; AD. 2 pp. Photostat. Original owned by James Monroe Museum and Memorial Library, Fredericksburg. #3159.
    Sine, cosine, tangent, and cotangent tables on recto. More tables with triangular forms on verso.
    [3165]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON MAP OF CANAL AND SAW MILL., AD. 1 pp. 7 3/4" x 9 3/4". Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533. See Nichols, N-487.
    [3130]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON MAP OF CHARLOTTESVILLE AND MILTON., AD. 1 pp. 16" x 10". Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [3131, N-557]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON MAP OF JAMES RIVER AND FLUVANNA RIVER FROM RICHMOND TO MONTICELLO., AD. 1 pp. 7 1/4" x 14 5/8. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [3133, N-559]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON MARGINAL NOTES IN COPY OF THE FIRST COLLECTION OF VOLUME THE SECOND OF THE MOSTE FAVOURITE MINUETS WITH THEIR BASSES (London, n.d.)., AD. 2 pp. Monticello Music Collection; owned by Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation. #3177-a.
    Method for tuning harpsichord.
    [3155]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON MATHEMATICAL NOTES., n.d.; AD. 2 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Method of cosecants.
    [3167]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, [Milton] to JAMES OLDHAM, at Mr. Gallego's, Richmond., Lettercover. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by Victor B. Levit. #8265-b.
    [3173]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON MUSIC., n.d.; AD. 3 pp. Owned by Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation. #5118.
    The Adieu, Love and Opportunity, The Pleasures of the Town, Minuet de la cour, Air de l'Epreuve villageoise, and Money Musk.
    [3150]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON MUSIC., n.d.; AD. 2 pp. Monticello Music Collection; owned by Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation. #3177-a.
    Not titled.
    [3151]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTE DESCRIBING LAND EXTENDING FROM RIVANNA RIVER TO MONTICELLO MOUNTAIN., AD. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [3113]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES AND SKETCHES FOR BUILDING A "PORTABLE FRAME FOR [CONSTRUCTING] RIDGES., AD. Fragment. 1 pp. McGregor Library, #3620.
    With two sketches of this device for protecting young plants.
    [3107, N-576]
  - [THOMAS JEFFERSON]. NOTES ON CONSTRUCTING AN ELLIPSE., n.d.; D. 1 pp. 19th century copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    [2339]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON DIGGING A HA! HA! MOAT., AD. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by James Monroe Museum and Memorial Library, Fredericksburg. #3159.
    Lists slaves who are diggers of this trench.
    [3108]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON DISTANCES IN POLES., AD. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Survey of a road, partly on lands of N. M. L[ewis].
    [3104]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON ELEVATIONS IN FRENCH AND ENGLISH TERMS., AD. 1 pp. McGregor Library, #3620.
    Mentions river, Monticello, and Montalto with [barometric readings?] at each site.
    [3149]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON FLOWER GARDENING., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. McGregor Library, #3620.
    [3106]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON HERBS., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    [2340]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON "HORSE WHEELS" FOR MILLS AT LEGO AND TUFTON., AD. 1 pp. McGregor Library, #3620.
    On verso of similar notes in unidentified hand.
    [3109, N-564]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON HOUSEHOLD SUPPLIES FOR ONE QUARTER., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by James Monroe Museum and Memorial Library, Fredericksburg. #3159.
    Spirits, whiskey, salt, brown sugar, white sugar, tea, coffee, cotton, and candles.
    [3110]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON HOW FAR THINGS ARE VISIBLE FROM MONTICELLO. AD., n.d.; Fragment. 1 pp. McGregor Library, #3620.
    English and French measurements.
    [3111]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON LIVESTOCK., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. On verso of lettercover, [?] to T. J., Milton. McGregor Library, #3620.
    [3114]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON LIVESTOCK AT MONTICELLO, TUFTON, AND LEGO., AD. 1 pp. On verso of lettercover, [?] to [?], ATTORNIES AT LAW, Charlottesville. McGregor Library, #3620.
    [3115]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON NAIL SIZES., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by James Monroe Museum and Memorial Library, Fredericksburg. #3159.
    [3116]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON SUN., n.d.; AD. 2 pp. Owned by Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation. #5118.
    Mentions London, Paris, and Fry-Jefferson map. On verso are notes on winds, comparing Williamsburg and Monticello.
    [3117]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES on a SURVEY in FAUQUIER COUNTY, VA., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. Photostat. #38-755.
    Original unknown.
    [2341]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES ON TIN AND PLANKING NEEDED AT MONTICELLO., AD. 2 pp. Photostat. Original owned by James Monroe Museum and Memorial Library, Fredericksburg. #3159.
    [3118]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES, UNIDENTIFIED., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by James Monroe Museum and Memorial Library, Fredericksburg. #3159.
    Perhaps index to mathematics book.
    [3120]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON NOTES FOR USE OF BORDA'S CIRCLE., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. Edgehill Randolph Papers. #5533.
    Includes formula for correction of instrumental error.
    [3169]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON PLAN FOR OCTAGONAL BUILDING., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. 4 3/4" x 8 1/4". Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533. See Nichols, N-496.
    Unidentified.
    [3140]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON PLAT OF HARRISON FAMILY LAND., AD. 1 pp. 15" x 11". Owned by Mrs. Edwin Page Kirk. #5291.
    Mr. Harrison's mill and Woodson's Ferry.
    [3132, N-558]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON PLAT OF MONTICELLO., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. 11" x 15 3/8". Owned by Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation. #5348.
    [3135, N-526-B]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON ALBEMARLE COUNTY. PLAT OF NICHOLAS M. LEWIS' LAND., AD. 1 pp. 3" x 5 1/4. Owned by Mrs. Edwin Page Kirk. #5291.
    [3134, N-560]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON POEMS., n.d.; AD. 2 pp. #6004.
    Tweed Side and To Maggy My Love I Did Tell.
    [3152]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON "RAILING OF TERRASSES.", n.d.; Ink. Paper CX. 7 3/4 x 10 in. Scale: full size. #171.
    [N-370]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON SURVEY MAP., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. 12 3/8" x 8". Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [3142]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON SURVEY MAP., n.d.; AD. 2 pp. 21" x 16". Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [3143]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON SURVEY MAP OF MONTICELLO., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. 15" x 20". Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [3136, N-526-D]
  - MAP OF EDGEHILL, SHADWELL, LEGO AND PANTOPS., AD. 1 pp. 16 3/8" x 20 3/8". Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [3137, N-526-C]
  - MAP AND SURVEY OF SHADWELL, PANTOPS, LEGO, AND EDGEHILL., AD. Fragment, 2 pp. 9 1/2" x 16". Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [3138, N-526-E]
  - SURVEY MAP., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. 12 3/8" x 8". Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [3142, N-526-F]
  - SURVEY MAP., n.d.; AD. 2 pp. 21" x 16 1/2". Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [3143, N-526-G]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON SURVEY NOTES., n.d.; AD. 4 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [3144]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON TABLE OF MILEAGES, MONTICELLO TO POPLAR FOREST, BEDFORD COUNTY., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. #6696.
    Monticello, Carter's Bridge, Warren Ferry, Gibson's gate, Raleigh, Mrs. Flood's, H. Flood's, Hunter's, Candler's, Limestone Bridge, Poplar Forest, Campbell Court House, Flat Creek, Waterlick, Turnpike, my road, western gate, and Poplar Forest house.
    [3147]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., Monticello., LETTERCOVER. 1 pp. Owned by George Green Shackelford. #5333.
    Draft of letter in unidentified hand.
    [3156]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to [?]., n.d.; ALS. Letterpress copy. Fragment. 1 pp. Last page only. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Mentions Congressional campaign.
    [3123]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to [?]., n.d.; ALS. Letterpress copy. Fragment. 1 pp. Last page only. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Land and slave sales.
    [3124]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to [?]., n.d.; ALS. Fragment. 2 pp. #6085.
    Scientific discussion.
    [3125]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON UNIDENTIFIED MARKINGS., n.d.; AD. 2 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Perhaps wrappers. "1st day: plat" and "to be decyphered."
    [3162]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA. ELEVATION AND SECTION OF DORMITORIES, SHOWING COLONNADES AND "ROOFLETS.", Ink. Paper CZ. 22 x 7 1/4 in. "Scale: 3 I to the line." #171.
    [N-367, K-31]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA. ELEVATION OF PAVILION X., n.d.; Ink and wash. Thin paper, no watermark. 6 3/4 x 8 in. #171.
    Drawn by John Neilson?
    [N-353, K-Pl. 17]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA. ELEVATION OF A TUSCAN COLUMN., n.d.; Ink. Scale: 2' = 1". Paper CZ. 5 1/2 x 19 1/4. #171.
    [N-372]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA. FRAGMENT OF A STUDY FOR THE PLAN OF THE ROTUNDA., Ink. Paper CZ. 7 1/2 x 10 3/4 in. with 2 3/4 x 7 3/4 in. portion cut out. #171.
    [N-333]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA. OBSERVATORY., n.d.; Ink. Scale: 10' = 1". Paper BD. 8 x 7 1/2 in. #171.
    Specifications on back.
    [N-381]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA. STUDY FOR OBSERVATORY., n.d.; Pencil. Scale: 10' = 1". Paper BD. 8 1/4 x 11 3/4 in. #171.
    [N-380]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA. THIRD VARIANT FOR RANGE AND GARDENS, SHOWING SERPENTINE WALLS., Ink. Paper CZ. 15 3/4 x 6 1/2 in. Scale: 40' = 1". #171.
    See N-305, N-306, and N-366.
    [N-369]
  - TUSCAN COLUMN AND BASE., Rendered in wash. Paper CX. 8 x 9 in. #171.
    Perhaps a study by to Mills to teach Cornelia J. Randolph rendering.
    [N-502]
  - UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA? ARCHITRAVE?, n.d.; Fragment, badly damaged. 10 1/4 x 17 in. RG-1/3/3.761.
    [N-378]
  - UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA. "DESCRIPTION OF A JOINT OR SPLICE," WITH A CUTOUT MODEL., n.d.; #5533.
    [N-379]
  - UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA. NOTE TO JEFFERSON SIGNED J. DINSMORE, REGARDING DIMENSIONS OF THE UNIVERSITY., n.d.; Paper CX. 6 1/2 x 3 1/2 in. #171.
    [N-373]
  - [?] to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., n.d.; LETTERCOVERS. 5 items, each 1 pp. #5385-t.
    Includes one franked by William Wirt as Attorney General of U.S.
    [3157]
  - [?] to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., n.d.; LETTERCOVERS. 2 items, each 1 pp. Owned by Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation. #5385-n.
    [3158]
  - [?], to THOMAS JEFFERSON., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. Lettercover. Owned by Gordon Trist Burke. #5385-u.
    [3160]
  - [?], to THOMAS JEFFERSON., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. Lettercover. Owned by Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation. #5385-f.
    Care of Mr. Brown.
    [3161]
  - JOHN CLIFTON, SKETCH OF MONTICELLO., n.d.; 1 pp. Pen and ink. 8x12 cm. #10059.
  - J. B. LONGACRE, PORTRAIT OF THOMAS JEFFERSON., n.d.; 1 pp. Watercolor. 8x6 cm. #10059.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, NOTE., n.d.; AN. 1 pp. RG-1/3/3.761.
    "Candidates for Professorships"
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to [FREDERICK W.] HATCH., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. Lettercover. McGregor Library, #2988.
  - SURVEY AND PLAT OF LAND IN BEDFORD COUNTY ON WOLF BRANCH, AD. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Owned by T. J.?
  - [?], to THOMAS JEFFERSON., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. Lettercover. #5385-ac. Owned by Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation.
    Postmarked July 12.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, CALLING CARD., n.d.; D. 1 pp. Engraved. #8824-af.
  - MUTUAL ASSURANCE SOCIETY, RECEIPT FOR INSURANCE POLICY, n.d.; D. 1 pp. Printed. Signed by T. J. and William Dawson. Photostat. #5385-ah. Original owned by Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation.
  - LIST OF BALANCES DUE THE ESTATE OF PETER JEFFERSON., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. #6004.
    23 entries from "W. Harvie's book of the estate's accounts"
  - LETTER FRAGMENTS., n.d.; ALS. 2 fragments. One in T. J.'s hand. #7109.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, BALLAD., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. #9090-c.
    First line: "Last Valentine's day when bright Phoebus shone clear"
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, SONGS., n.d.; 2 items. Each: AD. 2 pp. #9090-c.
    In Italian. "La Primavera" and "La Partenza"
  - PLAT OF CARTER AND MAZZEI LAND., AD. 1 pp. In T. J.'s hand. #9200.
    Incomplete.
  - MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH for THOMAS JEFFERSON, ORDER FOR GOODS., AD. 1 pp. #9737.
    5 yards wide check, 1 large and 2 small hair brooms.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, NOTE FRAGMENT., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. #12505.
    "[not?] to have reason, and to have it useless and...employed, is nearly the same." At the bottom of T. J.'s note is a note pencilled in another hand "Written by Thomas Jefferson and left by him (?) between these leaves. H.A.W."
  - LIST OF EXPENSES FOR AN UNIDENTIFED FURNACE AND FOUNDRY., AD. 1 pp. #38-620. In T. J.'s hand?
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, ENVELOPE, to GEORGE HANNAH, ESQ., n.d.; AD. 1 pp. #7697.
  - MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH, FRAGMENT OF A POEM., AD. 1 pp. #38-415.
    First line begins: "Today he puts forth the tender leaves of hope ..."
    Removed from T. J.'s copy of Dictionnaire raisonné universel d'histoire naturelle
    (McGregor A 1767 .V34)
  - [SURVEY AND MAP OF CHARLOTTESVILLE TO MILTON]., AD. 1 pp. 17 3/4" x 22 1/2". Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Mileage from various points in upper right; unidentified hand.
    [N-526-A]
  - VIOLET PRESSED IN THOMAS JEFFERSON'S COPY OF BLACKSTONE'S COMMENTARIES., n.d.; KD660 .B52 1803.